Okay, so let's talk about some more
motivational theories in this video.
So in this section, I want to
talk about theory X, Y and Z,
right, when it comes to
motivation, more motivational theory.
So a theory X and Y was developed by
someone called McGregor, right,
Douglas McGregor.
And Theory X and Y is basically talking
about the styles of management, right?
Styles of a leader, styles of a manager.
So you have a theory X manager and a
theory Y manager.
A theory X manager is
someone that believes
that their workers are
inherently lazy, right?
They dislike work, they don't like to
work, they're not particularly intelligent
and therefore you have to be a
micromanager.
So a theory X manager is
more of a micromanager,
whereas a theory Y manager
is a bit more hands-off.
They believe that work is as natural as
rest and play, right?
that's a directly quoted from Douglas
McGregor.
Basically, they believe that you give the
right conditions to your employees,
right, to your workers, and the people
will be self-motivate.
Everybody self-motivated to do a good job,
right?
So a theory why manager is someone that is
more hands-off, right?
They'll delegate the work, and then
they'll assume it's going to get done.
They're there to help them, they're there
to help and assist the worker as well,
right?
but, you know, they
believe that their workers
are self-motivated, they'll go on with it.
They're not going to micro-manage them,
right?
They're more hands-off.
Then you have Theory Z, right,
by someone by the name of William Uchi,
and Theory Z is an extension of Theory Y,
right?
It's an extension of Theory Y,
and it's talking about a job for life.
You give the right conditions to your
employees, and it's going to increase
their loyalty, and that's
going to improve or rather
that's going to basically
give them a job for life, right?
You're given the right conditions, they'll
steer with you for
the rest of their career.
And obviously it's a little outdated now,
something like this theory.
However, this theory Z, just
as a side note, was specifically
developed actually for
the Japanese work culture.
So, you know, you give the right
conditions and then, you know,
the Japanese workforce, you know,
the team members will stay with you for
the rest, essentially for the rest of
their career.
In some ways, it was originally developed
for the Japanese work culture.
But as I said, many of
these theories, I mean, some
of these theories are a
little outdated now anyway.
Now, then you have Maslow, right,
Abraham Maslow.
What Maslow is saying is you
have these five basic needs,
or rather everybody has
these five basic needs, right?
I have physiological needs, safety needs,
social needs, also known as love or
belonging needs, esteem needs,
self-actualization.
And you have to fulfill
the lower-level needs
before you can ascend
to the higher-level needs.
Lower-level needs then are the bottom
three.
Physiological, safety and social needs,
love and belonging, social needs.
Those three are the
lower-level needs, and then the
higher-level needs are
esteem and self-actualization.
So physiological needs, then, where be
things like food and shelter, right?
safety needs, having some kind of
security, some kind of stability, right?
Social needs, right, love and belonging,
right?
Some kind of family or some kind of sense
of belonging, essentially, right?
Then esteem needs, right, would be
self-confidence and then
self-actualization, what
you're trying to achieve
in life, where you're
trying to head in life.
Now, what Maslow is basically saying is if
you don't even meet your basic
physiological needs, right, your food and
shelter needs, you don't know where you're
sleeping tonight or, you know,
where your next meal is coming from,
you don't really care about anything else
above.
This is what you want to focus on first
before you ascend up here.
So in an office environment, for example,
if this was in a work environment,
your physiological needs would be,
say, your base income.
Your safety needs could be your bonuses
and your benefits.
Your social needs could
be your office buddies,
your esteem needs could be your job title.
And then self-actualization, what are you
trying to achieve in this organization?
Where are you trying to head in this
organization?
So if you don't even meet your basic
salary and, say, your benefit and bonus
needs, you know that you're
underappreciated, right?
You're undervalued, your
salary is really is much
lower than, you know,
what you should be getting.
You don't really care.
about what you're heading, you know,
where you're heading in this organization.
You don't really care about your job title
at that point.
I mean, essentially, if you
are not being paid your job
title, you don't really care
about what your job title is.
So you want to first fulfill these steps
down here or you want to fulfill these
levels down here before,
you know, you really
care about ascending to
these top levels up here.
So anyway, that's just a theory,
right?
So again, Although, you know, many of
these theories or some of these theories
can be, you know, may
sound a little outdated, but
they can still be asked
about in the exam, right?
Some, even all theories
are still relevant, you
know, to some extent in
this day and age, right?
But again, these are some theories that
may be asked about on the exam.